SHAMPEE BARUA

9/4 Macintosh St, Mascot . NSW 2020 . Phone: (61) 416650737 . shampee_barua@yahoo.com

CAREER SUMMARY

Naturally creative, resourceful and multi-talented Graphic & Web Designer with 1-year project experience in multimedia and print media. Possess excellent knowledge of Creative Suite 6 and HTML, CSS with strong ability to work in a fast-paced environment with par excellence work quality and exceptional administrative and customer service skills with a smile. Eager for full-time position in an organisation that values hard work and the capacity to grow.

KEY SKILLS

- A strong knowledge and experience of creating hand coded HTML, CSS & JavaScript
- Experience in web page design layout
- Programming experience in JavaScript and PHP
- Image creation and manipulation in a package such as Photoshop or fireworks
- Impeccable organizational, administrative and time management skills with strong ability to multitask under strict deadlines with attention to details.
- Proven ability to relate and communicate with peers and supervisors and excellent written skills.
- Motivated team player with a high degree of initiative and dedicated work ethics with positive learning attitude.
- Strong commitment to organizational goals and values and strict adherence to policies, procedures and practices with ability to contribute creative ideas for continuous improvement.
- Interactive digital skill in developing and designing website on client and server basis.

EDUCATION

TAFE Hornsby College, NSW **Diploma of Website Development** (with **Distinction**), 2013

University of Dhaka, Bangladesh **Bachelor of Arts** (English Literature), 2007

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

Shopping USA, CA

http://shoppingusa.com.au/

01/2014

Responsibilities:

- Creating & Designing the website
- Updating and Uploading Content
- SEO
- Corresponding to client via email or phone
- Creating and sending newsletter

Assistant Web Designer

Berry Web Design, Oatlands NSW

09/2013 - 11/2013

Responsibilities:

- Setting up WordPress websites in a development environment.
- Entering website content into the development environment.

- Customising WordPress theme framework as per requirements provided by the Principal. Work involved following coding languages: HTML, CSS, PHP and Javascript.
- Communicating back to Principal progress of development.

TAFE Project Work

Feb13 – Nov13

Hornsby TAFE, NSW

Responsibilities:

- Creating a fully developed website
- Database driven content
- iQuery slideshows
- Latest CSS3 techniques

- Content Management System
- ASP.NET with C#
- SQL and database design
- Creating user friendly and functional web applications
- Web security testing
- Advanced PHP and MySql
- JS and PHP powered contact forms

Administration Assistant (Voluntary Work)

05/2012 - 11/2012

The Theosophical Society (Adyar Lending Library), Sydney, NSW

Responsibilities:

- Data Entry of membership and book records
- Administration of library services and office
- Managing lending and returns of library books
- Handling of phone inquiries and customer service

Editorial Assistant

01/2009 - 11/2011

WhatsOn City Guide Ltd, Dhaka www.whatson.uk.com

Responsibilities:

- Updating and uploading data and images on various sections in the website
- Writing: Features, Articles, News, Book and Film Reviews and Blogs
- Assisting the editing for the editorial team
- Researching, identifying and listing of sports, music and club events
- Contact point for Public Relations activities
- Managing the office administration
- Image resizing, deep etching, colour correcting and retouching

Achievement:

- -Produced numerous articles and consistently received positive feedbacks from readers
- -Increased online registration of members by 50% to 2,500 by developing trendy and hip web Content for university students in the UK

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Software: Ms Office (Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, Visio), Adobe Master Collection-CS6, Visual Studio, SQL Server Management Studio
- CMS: Wordpress
- Language: HTML5, XHTML, CSS3, Java Script, PHP, j-Query, ASP.Net C#, SQL, Ajax
- Strong internet research skills

LANGUAGE

English & Bengali - Strong oral & written communication skill

References available upon request